payupaisa.com 2013-03-22

# Payu Paisa

### Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of personally identifiable information collected from Sub-Merchants who use or may want to use our payment gateway services, as well as consumer information that we acquire in the course of our business. This Policy also covers the treatment of personally identifiable information that our back end technology providers / partners may share with it.

We respect your privacy and want to promote trust and confidence on the internet. As such, we feel it is necessary to disclose to you what information this site collects and tracks and what we do with the information that we collect.

Information security is critical to our business. We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input. We store information gathered on secure computers. The number of employees involved in the management of the data centre that have physical access to these computers is limited. We use advanced security technology to prevent our computers from being accessed by unauthorized persons. It is important for you (Sub-Merchant) to protect against unauthorized access to your Login ID/password and to your computer. Be sure to protect the password used to access our services.

Currently, we collect personal information of our Sub-Merchants, through the Sub-Merchant registration process, the service agreement that we execute and various submitted documents of the Sub-Merchant's creditability as required by us from time to time. We may ask customers to enter personal data when placing an order, such as name, address, phone number, credit card/ banking details and E-mail address. We use this data to protect the sub merchant and ourselves against risk. Some of our web pages use "cookies" so that we can better serve you with customized information and in some cases protect ourselves and the sub-merchant from the risk of fraud. Cookies are identifiers which a web site can send to your browser to keep on your computer to facilitate your next visit to our site. You can set your browser to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the option to decide whether or not to accept it. The information we collect and analyze is used to improve our service to you.

We also track information like the domain name from which you contact us, the pages you request, the products you buy, the referring site, and the time that you spend on the site. For everyone who visits our Sub-Merchant purchase page, we log IP addresses, the type of operating system that your computer uses, and the type of browser software used by you. From the IP address, we can determine the Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of your point of connectivity. This is done to protect ourselves and the sub-merchant from fraud risk.

If you are our Sub-Merchant then the personal information you provide - name, address, etc.-allows us to inform you about updates, or changes to the service and to notify you of products and services of [PayUPaisa.com](https://www.payu.in/), its backend service providers and affiliates that we believe may be of interest to you.

We use reasonable precautions to keep the personal information disclosed to us secure and do not disclose this information to other individuals or organizations unless required by law. However we will exchange information with other companies and organizations for the sole purposes of fraud protection and risk reduction. However, in the case of abuse or breach of security, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for any actions of any third parties which receive the information illegally. We will not distribute customer information to be used in mailing lists, surveys, or any other purpose other than what is required to perform our services. However we will send personally identifiable information about you (Sub-Merchants) to other companies or people when:

1\. we have your consent to share the information;  
2\. we need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested;  
3\. we need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of us to provide a product or service to you (unless we tell you differently these companies do not have any right to use the personally identifiable information we provide them beyond what is necessary to assist us).

Personally identifiable consumer information is also shared with third parties (such as our Acquiring banks and credit card processors) to the extent necessary for us to deliver payment processing services. We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our customers' personal data.

If you (i.e. our Sub-Merchant) would like to view the information we have collected from you and your customers or you want to correct your information or the billing/shipping details of your customers or their IP addresses, please go to Merchant Login page and log into your account to view the above details and to review your personal information. If you have questions or suggestions, we can be reached by email at [contact@payupaisa.com](mailto:contact@payupaisa.com)

We respond to government and/ or legal demands/orders regarding information that is contained within our access logs concerning Sub-Merchant(s), customer(s) or visitor(s). We reserve the right to share such information concerning to any Sub-Merchant(s) who we believe are in violation of our content guidelines, even without a government and/ or legal demands/orders.

We also reserve the right to report any illegal activity by our Sub-Merchants or their customers to law enforcement for prosecution. Please be aware that we do not control the acts of our Sub-Merchants, customers or visitors.

Please feel free contact us at [contact@payupaisa.com](mailto:contact@payupaisa.com) to highlight any issues that you may be facing or require any information/ assistance from us.
